You have probably heard that you should not lay all the eggs in the same basket.
In this video we will go through how to diversify its portfolio.
Now it is the same basket, but it is still important to have several assets in their basket.
Got reconciliation at a Snickers.
Allright, then we drive then.
In this video we will go through five good tips that I wish I got when I started investing.
I have seen a horribly many beginners who totally do away with them when investing.
So we will go through diversifications in this video.
It is important to spread your risk so that you do not lose money on the stock exchange.
For example, you invest all money in a company or that you may be all in cryptocurrencies or something else.
It can have horrific consequences for your portfolio and your money.
Believe me, I've learned the hard way.
Well, it simply means that you protect yourself against your own stupidity simply among your investments.
Do you have all your money in a business?
Yes, then it is true that if the company concentrates (go bankrupt) then you will lose all your money.
So for example, the seat belt, we do not have it for us to crash, but it is if we collide.
You do not know if it will go to hell.
So it's just as good to take it safe for the uncertain.
Then run thick!
Then drive!
The first tip when it comes to diversifying your portfolio is not to forget that you do not just need shares or funds in your portfolio.
Sure, when you are new then maybe it works, but when you start getting some more money in your portfolio then you may be wise to have several asset laws.
Yes, you can have art, you can have watches, you can have wine, you can have real estate.
There is a bunch of other investments that also go up in the long term to spread the risk in your portfolio.
Tip 2 - Diversify among multiple industries
And a simple tip there may be to think that you have a maximum of 25% of the portfolio in an individual industry.
And then max.
Look at several different industries.
Because it is so, if a certain industry is affected, then it may be that your entire portfolio goes down.
And for example, American shares have been doing very well now lately.
Many people buy global funds and American tech companies.
So remember to have not too much of your entire portfolio in a particular industry or niche.
Point number three.
Diversifying among several countries.
The same goes for countries and regions.
This year, for example, the US stock exchange has gone very strong.
And what happens then?
Well, all beginners rush into American tech shares such as Nvidia and the like.
At the same time, having some money on savings account with interest today you get 3-4% in a savings account.
Maybe a little peer-to-peer loan also that was a comfort last year for example, is quite nice.
And we get into cryptocurrencies and things like bitcoin.
Yes, it is an extremely high risk!
But a proposal there could be to have a maximum of 5-10% of your total portfolio against cryptocurrencies.
Some others advocate gold, silver and other precious metals,
But digital currencies, yes, they have actually historically given a pretty nice return over time.
But as I said, think about the high risk.
And speaking of Bitcoin and Ethereum, we come quite naturally to XBT Provider,
which is the sponsor of today's video.
Through XBT, such as Bitcoin-XBT, Ethereum-XBT, you can get exposure to cryptocurrencies
When everyone talks about the stock exchange and it is hottest.
But it is now when maybe no one is talking about shares and the stock exchange
As it might be a place to buy a little.
Then it depends on which company of course.
But instead of pushing all the money at once in shares,
Therefore, make sure to spread the purchases and drove you in.
If you have 10,000 to invest in shares, perhaps divide it into smaller portions,
Maybe a thousand kronor at a time, so you take in a little when it goes up and a little when it goes down.
For time you get a good average price, yes, which is better for you in the end.
And then you also reduce the risk of buying on a top and selling on a bottom.
So do you have any tips on how to best diversify their portfolio?